<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Breezey's Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-07-19T21:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Royal Society Summer Exhibition 2017</title><link href="/amazing-masers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2017-07-19T21:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Breeze</name></author><id>tag:,2017-07-19:amazing-masers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We (a joint venture between Imperial College London and University College London) recently exhibited at the &lt;a href="https://royalsociety.org/science-events-and-lectures/2017/summer-science-exhibition/"&gt;Royal Society Summer Exhibition 2017&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../images/amazing_masers_logo.png" width="50%") &lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our exhibit '&lt;a href="https://royalsociety.org/science-events-and-lectures/2017/summer-science-exhibition/exhibits/amazing-masers/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazing Masers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;' exhibit showcased our room-temperature maser, the first time it has been outside a lab. We also encouraged visitors to build pentacene, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;-terphenyl and other molecules and test drive a robotic mars rover on a CNC machined model of the surface of Mars via a video feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's our video that explains what masers are, what they do and what they could do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="775" height="436" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nBCSh5ivLYQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to our volunteers we had a very successful week with only a few minor technical hitches.  We hope that our visitors enjoyed the exhibit and learnt about masers and their new exciting future.  &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="masers"></category><category term="royal society"></category></entry><entry><title>About me, about that ...</title><link href="/about.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2017-07-17T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Breeze</name></author><id>tag:,2017-07-17:about.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a physicist (originally astrophysist) currently working as a Research Fellow at &lt;a href="http://www.imperial.ac.uk/"&gt;Imperial College London&lt;/a&gt; in the Department of Materials.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked in the space industry for a fair few years – designing passive microwave equipment for spacecraft payloads – until I returned to academia to do a PhD in materials physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PhD focussed on microwave absorption in metal-oxides, using density functional theory to predict phonon dispersion and anharmonic phonon-phonon interactions.  These results were fed into a quantum field theory of anharmonic phonons and compared (successfully) to measured properties of real metal-oxide crystals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main research interests are electro-magnetics, materials physics, numerical modeling, spin-physics and cavity quantum electrodynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am co-inventor of the room-temperature solid-state maser and have recently been dedicating my time to improving the devices through better understanding of the spin-physics and electro-magnetic design.  Our &lt;a href="http://www.imperial.ac.uk/maser"&gt;maser research team&lt;/a&gt; is very interdisciplinary – combining the efforts of physicists, chemists and engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as getting stuck into mathematics on the theory side, my industrial experience means that I am also quite handy at conducting experiments.  I use code to enhance my efforts in both – from parallel high performance and GPU computing to writing drivers for instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly use C/C++, Python and Julia for these purposes, but also code in JavaScript (HTML and Node.js), Perl, and Fortran.  Back in the day I coded in machine-code/assembler (Z80, 6502, 68000), but those days are past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imperial.ac.uk/people/jonathan.breeze"&gt;Imperial College Personal Web Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Publications</title><link href="/pubs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2017-07-17T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Jon Breeze</name></author><id>tag:,2017-07-17:pubs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Books&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.springer.com/gb/book/9783319445458"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature and Frequency Dependence of Complex Permittivity in Metal Oxide Dielectrics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze J, Publisher: Springer, ISBN: 9783319445458 (2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Selected Journal Papers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nanosecond time-resolved characterization of a pentacene-based room-temperature MASER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Salvadori E, Breeze JD, Tan K-J, Sathian J, Richards B, Fung MW, Wolfowicz G, Oxborrow M, Alford NM, Kay CWMet al., Scientific Reports, Vol: 7 (2017)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solid-state source of intense yellow light based on a Ce:YAG luminescent concentrator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sathian J, Breeze JD, Richards B, Alford NM, Oxborrow Met al., Optics Express, Vol: 25, Pages: 13714-13727 (2017)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Molecular Design of a Room-Temperature Maser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bogatko S, Haynes PD, Sathian J, Wade J, Kim J-S, Tan K-J, Breeze J, Salvadori E, Horsfield A, Oxborrow Met al.,  JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY C, Vol: 120, Pages: 8251-8260, (2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced magnetic Purcell effect in room-temperature masers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze J, Tan K-J, Richards B, Sathian J, Oxborrow M, Alford NMet al., Nature Communications, Vol: 6, (2015)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rectenna device: From theory to practice (a review)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Donchev E, Pang JS, Gammon PM, Centeno A, Xie F, Petrov PK, Breeze JD, Ryan MP, Riley DJ, Alford NMet al., MRS Energy &amp;amp; Sustainability, Vol: 1, (2014)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spectroscopic ellipsometry as an optical probe of strain evolution in ferroelectric thin films&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Lei DY, Kena-Cohen S, Zou B, Petrov PK, Sonnefraud Y, Breeze J, Maier SA, Alford NMet al., OPTICS EXPRESS, Vol: 20, Pages: 4419-4427, (2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Room-temperature solid-state maser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Oxborrow M, Breeze JD, Alford NM, 2012, NATURE, Vol: 488, Pages: 353-+, ISSN: 0028-0836&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better than Bragg: Optimizing the quality factor of resonators with aperiodic dielectric reflectors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze J, Oxborrow M, Alford NM, 2011, APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, Vol: 99, ISSN: 0003-6951&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scattering of light into silicon by spherical and hemispherical silver nanoparticles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Centeno A, Breeze J, Ahmed B, Reehal H, Alford Net al., 2010, , OPTICS LETTERS, Vol: 35, Pages: 76-78, ISSN: 0146-9592&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intrinsic Microwave Dielectric Loss of Lanthanum Aluminate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Shimada T, Ichikawa K, Minemura T, Yamauchi H, Utsumi W, Ishii Y, Breeze J, Alford NMet al., 2010, IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ULTRASONICS FERROELECTRICS AND FREQUENCY CONTROL, Vol: 57, Pages: 2243-2249, ISSN: 0885-3010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature-stable and high Q-factor TiO2 Bragg reflector resonator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze J, Krupka J, Centeno A, Alford NMet al., 2009, APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, Vol: 94, ISSN: 0003-6951&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do Grain Boundaries Affect Microwave Dielectric Loss in Oxides?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze JD, Perkins JM, McComb DW, Alford NMet al., 2009, JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN CERAMIC SOCIETY, Vol: 92, Pages: 671-674, ISSN: 0002-7820&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced quality factors in aperiodic reflector resonators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze J, Krupka J, Alford NM, 2007, APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, Vol: 91, ISSN: 0003-6951&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quasi-classical fluctuation-dissipation description of dielectric loss in oxides with implications for quantum information processing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Dunne LJ, Axelsson AK, Alford NM, Breeze J, Aupi X, Brandas EJet al., 2006, INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF QUANTUM CHEMISTRY, Vol: 106, Pages: 986-993, ISSN: 0020-7608&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measurements of permittivity, dieletric loss tangent, and resistivity of float-zone silicon at microwave frequencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Krupka J, Breeze J, Centeno A, Alford N, Claussen T, Jensen Let al., 2006, IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON MICROWAVE THEORY AND TECHNIQUES, Vol: 54, Pages: 3995-4001, ISSN: 0018-9480&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characterization and microwave dielectric properties of M2+Nb2O6 ceramics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pullar RC, Breeze JD, Alford NM, 2005, JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN CERAMIC SOCIETY, Vol: 88, Pages: 2466-2471, ISSN: 0002-7820&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microwave dielectric loss in oxides: Theory and experiment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Aupi X, Breeze J, Ljepojevic N, Dunne LJ, Malde N, Axelsson AK, Alford NMet al., 2004, JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, Vol: 95, Pages: 2639-2645, ISSN: 0021-8979&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Piezoelectrically tuned dielectric resonators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Alford NM, Petrov PK, Breeze J, Sarma KSet al., 2002, ELECTRONICS LETTERS, Vol: 38, Pages: 855-857, ISSN: 0013-5194&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultralow loss polycrystalline alumina&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze JD, Aupi X, Alford NM, 2002, APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, Vol: 81, Pages: 5021-5023, ISSN: 0003-6951&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raman spectroscopic study of gallium-doped Ba(Zn1/3Ta2/3)O-3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Webb SJ, Breeze J, Scott RI, Cannell DS, Iddles DM, Alford NMet al., 2002, JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN CERAMIC SOCIETY, Vol: 85, Pages: 1753-1756, ISSN: 0002-7820&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the temperature coefficient of resonant frequency in microwave dielectrics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Reaney IM, Wise P, Ubic R, Breeze J, Alford NM, Iddles D, Cannell D, Price Tet al., 2001, PHILOSOPHICAL MAGAZINE A-PHYSICS OF CONDENSED MATTER STRUCTURE DEFECTS AND MECHANICAL PROPERTIES, Vol: 81, Pages: 501-510, ISSN: 0141-8610&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layered Al2O3-TiO2 composite dielectric resonators with tuneable temperature coefficient for microwave applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Alford NM, Breeze J, Penn SJ, Poole Met al., 2000, IEE Proceedings: Science, Measurement and Technology, Vol: 147, Pages: 269-273, ISSN: 1350-2344&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layered Al2O3-TiO2 composite dielectric resonators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Breeze J, Penn SJ, Poole M, Alford NMet al., 2000, ELECTRONICS LETTERS, Vol: 36, Pages: 883-884, ISSN: 0013-5194&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>